Ginevra Terenghi



ginevra.terenghi@gmail.com +39 3338889379 (IT) +44 7432267566 (UK)

@ginevraterenghi

Portfolio: https://gi nevraterenghi .githu b. io/portfol io/

I am a Designer specialized in Graphic and Information Design and interested in doing research about the Visual methods able to better drive the interface designing and the complex phenomena and data Communication.

I have an experimental approach. I do like mixing contents and look for different paths to reach the solution from unusual perspectives.

EXPERIENCE

Data Sonification and Visualization Speaker

King's College London, January 2020 Insight presentation and tutorial about Data Sonification and Visualization during the Air Pollution Data Activism Workshop.

Digital Methods Facilitator

University of Amsterdam, Summer School 2018 - Winter School 2019 Journalist and coders training in data visualization techniques. Infographics designing to find and summarize insight in complex phenomena.

Graphic and Information Designer

DensityDesign Research Lab, March 2018 - January 2019
Dashboard and visual interface designing to represent data and complex issues.

Data Visualization Designer

Harvard University (Data-Shack Program), January 2018 - May 2018 Data visualization and visual interface prototyping to communicate algorithmic results, with the collaboration of data scientist and informatic engineers.

EDUCATION

Communication Design - MA

Politecnico di Milano, April 2019 - March 2016 110 cum laude/110

Media Languages - BA

Università Cattolica del Sacro Cuore, Milano Juyl 2015 - September 2012 Milano 108/110

SKILLS

Adobe Suite
Microsoft Suite (Excel)
Ablaton (music and sou

Ableton (music and sound creation)

Creative Coding: Html, CSS

Data Viz programs: Tableau, QGIS, Gephi

Able to work with people with different backgrounds; good organizer and work coordinator; able to work under stress on short deadlines.